Welcome back!
欢迎回来!
In the previous step, we solved the simple problem in a structured approach, and in this step we would
在上一步中，我们用结构化的方法解决了这个简单的问题，而在这一步中，我们将关注如何用功能化的方法解决这个问题。
want to focus on how to solve it in a functional approach.
我们想把重点放在如何用功能方法来解决这个问题上。
What I'll do is, I'll copy this file and paste it down here. I'll rename it to, FP01Functional.
我要做的是，复制这个文件并将其粘贴到这里。我将把它重命名为：FP01Functional。
Let's open up FP01Functional and that's where we'll try and solve this problem.
让我们打开FP01Functional，这就是我们要尝试解决这个问题的地方。
Let's start with renaming the method.
让我们从重命名该方法开始。
Right click, Refactor, Rename, and I would want to rename this to
右键，重构，重命名，我想把它重命名为
printAllNumbersInList, in a Functional approach. That's what we would want to do.
printAllNumbersInList，采用函数式方法。这就是我们想要做的。
So, we'd want to print all the numbers in a Functional approach.
所以，我们想用函数式方法打印所有的数字。
We have a list of numbers passed in.
我们有一个传入的数字列表。
Now, how do we do this in a Functional approach?
现在，我们如何在函数式方法中做到这一点呢？
One of the important things to remember is, in the functional approach, we will focus on, 'What to do?'
需要记住的一件事是，在函数式方法中，我们将专注于："做什么？
Before we can focus on what to do,
在我们能够关注做什么之前、
what we'd need to do is, we'd need to convert the list of numbers into a stream of numbers.
我们需要做的是，我们需要将数字列表转换成数字流。
What does that mean?
那是什么意思？
You can see, that the list of numbers is this. You'd want to convert this into a stream.
你可以看到，数字的列表是这样的。你想把它转换为一个流。
So, I would want to convert it into a sequence of elements.
所以，我想把它转换成一个元素的序列。
I would want to first get 12, then get 9, then get 13, then get 4,
我想首先得到12，然后得到9，然后得到13，然后得到4、
and so on and so forth.
以此类推。
So, we would want to convert whatever we have, into a stream of elements.
所以，我们想把我们拥有的任何东西转换成一个元素流。
How do we convert a list into a stream?
我们如何将一个列表转换为一个流呢？
The way we can do that is by; let's comment out this piece of code, Ctrl slash or Command slash,
我们可以这样做；让我们把这段代码注释出来，Ctrl斜线或Command斜线、
and followed by Ctrl Shift F or Command Shift F to format it. Cool! That's commented out.
然后用Ctrl Shift F或Command Shift F来格式化它。酷！这就是注释！这就是注释出来的。
We'd want to create a stream for numbers. So, numbers.stream.
我们想为数字创建一个流。所以，numbers.stream。
As you can see in the Java doc, it says, "Returns a sequential Stream with this collection as its source."
正如你在Java文档中看到的，它说："返回一个以这个集合为源的连续的流"。
So, we're taking a list and converting it into a stream of numbers.
所以，我们要把一个列表转换为一个数字流。
So, we are converting it into individual numbers, which come one after the other;
所以，我们要把它转换成单个的数字，这些数字一个接一个地出现；
a sequence of numbers: 12, 9, 13, 4. Once I have a stream of numbers,
一系列的数字： 12, 9, 13, 4. 一旦我有了一个数字流，我可以做的是指定每个数字的处理方法、
what I can do is to specify, what to do with each one of them.
我可以做的是指定对每个数字做什么。
So when I get 12, what needs to be done? When I get 9, what needs to be done?
因此，当我得到12时，需要做什么？当我得到9时，需要做什么？
What do we want to do with each one of them?
我们想对它们中的每一个做什么？
We'd want to do a System.out.println(number) right?
我们想做一个System.out.println(number)，对吗？
So what we'll do is, we'll create a simple method, which accepts a parameter and prints it out.
所以我们要做的是，创建一个简单的方法，它接受一个参数并将其打印出来。
So, let's create a simple method in here.
所以，让我们在这里创建一个简单的方法。
So, I call this private static void.
所以，我把这个方法称为私有静态无效。
I'll just call this, print and let's send
我将只是调用这个，打印并让我们发送
in a int number to it.
输入一个数字。
What this will do is, it will just do a System.out.println(number).
这将做的是，它将只是做一个System.out.println(number)。
So, it just prints a single number, that's it.
所以，它只是打印出一个数字，仅此而已。
Nothing more, nothing less.
没有别的，也没有别的。
Now, what do we want to do over here?
现在，我们想在这里做什么？
numbers.stream() for each number. For each of these numbers, for 12, for 9, for 13, for 4,
numbers.stream() 对于每个数字。对于每一个数字，12，9，13，4、
we would want to call the print method.
我们想调用打印方法。
How do we call the print method from here,
我们如何从这里调用打印方法、
for each of the numbers? The way we can do that is by
的方法？我们可以这样做的方法是
saying, forEach, and you can define;
说，forEach，你可以定义；
I would want to call the print method. Now, over here,
我想调用打印方法。现在，在这里、
typically what we'd do, we'll say print of 5.
通常我们会做什么，我们会说print of 5。
Alright! So, typically what would happen?
好吧！那么，通常会发生什么呢？那么，通常会发生什么？
This code would be immediately executed.
这段代码会被立即执行。
We don't want the method to be immediately called. What we would want
我们不希望这个方法被立即调用。我们想做的是
to do is to define, what needs to be done.
做的是定义需要做什么。
We need to define the behavior, when we get a number of 12.
我们需要定义行为，当我们得到一个12的数字时。
To define the behavior, we use something called a method reference.
为了定义这个行为，我们使用了一个叫做方法引用的东西。
How do you put a method reference in?
你怎么把一个方法引用放进去？
What we want to do is, for each element we'd want to call this print method.
我们要做的是，对于每个元素，我们要调用这个打印方法。
How do we say that? The way we can say that is by using, the name of the class, colon,
我们怎么说呢？我们可以通过使用类的名称，冒号来表达、
colon, followed by the name of the method.
冒号，然后是方法的名称。
So, you can see that this is a static method and I'm using the class name colon, colon the name of the
所以，你可以看到这是一个静态方法，我使用了类的名称冒号，冒号，然后是方法的名称。
static method. And what I'm telling it is, hey! take the numbers, convert in into a stream,
静态方法。我告诉它的是，嘿！把这些数字，转换为一个流、
and for each element; for 12 do a print, for 9 do a print.
对每一个元素；对12做一个打印，对9做一个打印。
That's basically, what we are specifying in here.
基本上，这就是我们在这里指定的内容。
Now, I think we have got almost everything covered. So let's do Right click, Run As, Java Application.
现在，我想我们已经得到了几乎所有的东西。所以，让我们点击右键，以运行方式运行，Java应用程序。
Aha! The output does not really change.
啊哈！输出并没有真正改变。
You can see that, everything is being printed out in a sequence.
你可以看到，所有的东西都是按顺序打印出来的。
Let's end this step by reviewing quickly, what's happening with this code.
让我们快速回顾一下这一步，这段代码发生了什么。
What we are doing is, we are converting the numbers list into a stream.
我们正在做的是，我们正在将数字列表转换成一个流。
So instead of getting a list like this, what we'll get is, a stream of elements like this.
所以我们得到的不是这样的一个列表，而是这样的一个元素流。
And what we are specifying is, for each of these elements which are coming out, what we would want to
我们所指定的是，对于每一个出来的元素，我们想做的是
do is, to call the print method which is present in the current class.
是，调用当前类中的打印方法。
And the syntax which we are using in here is, colon, colon.
我们在这里使用的语法是，冒号，冒号。
This is the syntax of something called a Method Reference.
这是一种叫做方法引用的语法。
What we are saying in here is, for each element, this method needs to be called.
我们在这里说的是，对于每个元素，这个方法都需要被调用。
So, for each of the numbers coming up, what would happen is, this print method would get executed
所以，对于每一个出现的数字，会发生什么，这个打印方法会被执行
and that's how we were seeing all the elements that are printed.
这就是我们如何看到所有被打印的元素。
I'm sure there are a lot of questions about this specific approach.
我相信有很多关于这个具体方法的问题。
Hold onto them, and I'll see you in the next step.
请抓紧时间，我们在下一步见。